[Episode 25]
So, you're Xing Wu.
I'm Qing Ye's father.
Ye is coming back home with me tomorrow.
I know.
I need to ask you something.
Sure. What is it?
After Ye returns to Beijing,
I don't want you two staying in touch.
You shouldn't bring this to me.
Who she talks to
is up to her.
She is my daughter.
And as a father,
I'm not going to let anyone
get in the way of her bright future.
She still holds unrealistic ideas about life.
But once she's back in Beijing, she will see
that you two
live in completely different worlds.
Give it time,
she'll gradually forget about you.
Your paths
will never cross again.
Then so be it.
As long as she's doing well.
If that's all,
I'll get going.
Uncle Qing,
After Qing Ye goes back,
please spend more time with her.
She's tough
and independent,
but she still gets lonely.
She needs love from her family.
So suddenly.
I haven't prepared anything.
I don't even have
a decent goodbye gift for you.
Your skill is the best gift.
Just give me a nice haircut.
That's more than enough.
You're such a sweet talker.
When I was young,
I had hair
just as nice as yours.
You must've been stunning, Auntie.
Stunning? No.
Stupid is more like it.
I remember
dating a guy
my mother didn't approve of.
Your mom also told me
to break up with him,
but I wouldn't listen.
I thought they just
didn't get me,
didn't understand love.
In a fit of pique,
I ran away with him.
And look at me now.
Your Auntie ended up like this.
Full of regrets.
But in life,
there's no undo button.
So don't be stubborn with your dad.
Don't let anger
push you onto the wrong path.
No parent
in this world
wants to harm their child.
How do I know what the right path is?
Come here,
let me take a look.
Okay.
Go home with your dad.
Big house,
nice clothes.
When you want to study,
study hard.
When you want to have fun,
have fun.
Never worry about money again.
That is
the right path.
There, all done.
Auntie,
the hairstyle you did is really beautiful.
Well,
my skill
is still decent after all.
Ye, you look gorgeous.
You awake?
Woke up as soon as you came in.
I...
brought you some Tanghulu.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
Yeah, I heard.
It's my last night here.
I should do something.
I feel like
it would be a pity
to just sleep through it.
What do you want to do?
I'm with you.
So much better sitting in the front!
As if you've never sat on my bike before.
Yeah, but never in the front!
It's a completely different feeling.
You know how to fly a plane.
You know how to dive.
How come you can't handle a little angel?
How do you know that?
Because I'm your brother.
In all this time,
this is
the first time
I've just sat here quietly
and looked at the ocean in Zhazhating.
It looks like an oil painting.
Honestly,
it looks more like a circuit board to me.
How so?
Way to kill the mood.
See that spot over there?
I used to climb up there
all the time when I was little.
So that's like
your secret base?
You could say that.
Back then, Xing Guo Dong had a bad temper.
He was always hitting me.
So I'd sneak off by myself
and climb all the way up there.
Wouldn't he find you?
No.
Never.
I'd sit up there for the whole day,
watching the sun slowly set in the west,
the fishing boats return to the harbor,
and the sky gradually goes dark.
Weren't you scared?
I was.
I was terrified as a kid.
You don't notice it while climbing,
but then the wind gets strong,
you're too scared to come down.
Then...
Then what? What did you do?
Then I waited.
I'd wait until it got dark,
until the lighthouse came on.
I thought that light was for me.
Suddenly, I wasn't scared anymore.
After that, I'd climbed up there
by myself a lot.
I'd count down until the lighthouse lit up.
Just like right now.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Light up!
It's late.
Do you know what a lighthouse is for?
A landmark.
Exactly.
For a ship, a lighthouse is
a vital guide showing the way.
Qing Ye,
you're a born explorer.
It's time to set sail
and conquer your vast ocean.
There really is something
about Zhazhating.
The first time I came here,
I was desperate to leave.
The second time,
I was desperate to stay.
This time...
I was actually thinking
it'd be nice if you could come with me.
Once you leave this time,
don't ever come back.
Do you remember
what you said to me on New Year's Eve?
I haven't forgotten.
You said you'd be
wherever I wanted to be.
But with my current grades,
there's no way I'll get into
the same university as you,
let alone go abroad.
That's the truth.
Xing Wu.
I believe in you.
If you want to go,
you'll find a hundred different ways
to get there.
If you want to see me again,
then walk right up to me on your own.
Okay.
I promise you.
I'm applying to Qingbei University.
I'll cut the distance between us
in half.
The other half
is on you.
I'll do my best.
Give me your phone.
[Delete contact Qing Ye.]
[Are you sure you want to delete "Qing Ye"?]
[Delete / Cancel]
I'm deleting our contact information.
Until you catch up to me,
we won't be in touch.
[Delete contact Xing Wu.]
[Xing Wu: are you sure you want to
delete this contact? Cancel / Confirm]
Take this as motivation
to catch up to me.
I hope that the next time we meet,
we'll both be our best selves.
Qing Ye,
just keep moving forward.
I'll catch up.
Go back now.
You have work tomorrow.
I'll wait
until you're inside.
Will you come tomorrow?
Qing Ye,
don't look back.
Never mind.
You're more trouble than help.
I've been working
as fast as I can, and this is all I've got.
Qing Ye is leaving tomorrow morning.
How am I supposed to finish in time?
Qing Ye's dad, seriously?
Showing up out of nowhere
and leaving just as suddenly.
We weren't prepared at all.
Come to think of it,
Ye never really got to enjoy herself here.
Going back with her dad
is probably for the best.
Get in.
Where's your luggage?
It's still early.
Dad.
Let's go out for breakfast.
Here.
Try our signature seafood noodles.
Thank you.
Let me know what you need.
- Ye, take your time.
- Thank you, Auntie Shan Xi.
So the family
you're staying with runs a restaurant.
Yes.
They let us
stay in their house.
They're staying elsewhere for now.
No need to wipe it. It's clean.
It's been through the sterilizer.
You used to be so particular about cleanliness.
This place cures germaphobia.
Stay long enough
and you'll get used to it, too.
See that place across the street
that burned down?
[Xuan Island Barbershop]
I was
living there before.
I came here many years ago.
Didn't expect it to look like this.
At least you're okay.
When I first got here,
Auntie's family cooked with lard.
I couldn't stomach it,
so I went hungry for a day.
My first proper meal
was at this place.
I'm sorry.
I made you suffer.
I thought it was hard back then,
but when I look back,
I was quite happy.
Ye, you've grown up.
You're no longer the little girl
in my memory anymore.
Living in an environment like this,
you have to learn
to adapt
and find joy in the hard times.
That's how you get through the days.
After coming here,
I realized
how lonely our home in Beijing was
after Mom passed away.
Dad,
when you're starving,
would you still worry about
if someone else has enough to eat?
No.
They would.
The same day Xing Wu found out
I don't eat lard,
he switched to vegetable oil.
He changed
the lock on the bathroom shower
in the backyard,
the wardrobe,
the air conditioner and light in my bedroom.
Auntie was worried
I wasn't getting enough nutrition,
so she stewed me
pot after pot of pork trotters.
Grandma was afraid I'd lose things again,
so she knitted me all these custom covers
for my pens, my notebooks,
and my laptop.
You might think these are small things,
but each item
stands for their unconditional giving.
They treat me like family,
and I treat them like family, too.
So before I leave,
I want to do something for them.
Dad, try it.
The seafood noodles here are really good.
Fine.
Here is 100,000 yuan.
Consider it payment for
taking care of Ye all this time.
Please accept it.
You already paid me for taking care of Ye.
I can't accept this.
Last time I still owed you 20,000 yuan.
And your barbershop needs repairs.
This 100,000 yuan
should make things a little easier for you.
Having money is always better than not.
Yes.
You're right.
Who would turn down money?
Fine.
I'll take it.
But I'm writing you an IOU.
[IOU: I, Li Lan Fang,]
Units, tens, hundreds, thousands...
[hereby borrow 100,000 yuan from
Qing Hong Zhi on the Lantern Festival, 2025.]
Here.
Take a look.
I never expected you to pay it back.
I know.
But I'm going to.
I admit,
at first, I was only
looking after Ye for the money.
But after all this time together,
I've come to see her as my own niece.
So thank you, brother-in-law,
for lending me this money.
Even if it's just for Ye's sake,
I must pay this back.
If not in three years, then five.
If not five, then seven.
But
every single yuan will be repaid.
Here, Auntie.
Alright.
Everyone, enough for walking me out.
Or I'll never be able to leave.
Even better.
Then you stay.
I'll cover your food and board.
Stop it.
We can't keep her here anyway.
You're just making us all want to cry.
Ye,
Grandma and I wanted to
to give you something to remember us
when you go back,
but with
Xuan Island gone,
we don't have anything
decent enough to give you.
I wanted to knit you a scarf
to keep you warm on the road,
but I'm old and my hands
don't work like they used to.
I haven't finished it yet.
Grandma.
Grandma, you're not old.
You'll live to be 100.
How could I live that long?
You can. Because I said so.
Finish that scarf for me.
I'll come back for it next time.
Okay.
Grandma will be right here waiting for you.
Come back whenever you're free.
Grandma.
I'm going to miss you all so much.
I'll buy you that electric wheelchair
when I come back next time.
Don't you worry about that.
Look, this one works just fine.
When you are back,
take good care of yourself, okay?
Ye,
it's time to go.
Go on.
Don't keep your dad waiting.
And don't cry.
You came with a smile, so leave with it, too.
Otherwise, people will think
we bullied you or something.
Okay.
Grandma, I'm leaving now.
Alright.
There, there. Good girl.
Auntie Yu Fen,
Auntie Shan Xi,
Auntie,
I'm leaving.
Fuzz,
Hu,
see you next time.
Cousin,
are you really leaving?
Can't you just stay?
School starts the day after tomorrow.
What's our study group going to do without you?
Yeah.
I've already talked to Ye Ying Jian.
He'll keep leading your studies.
And I'll send you study materials regularly.
We're a team.
Don't let me down.
Thank you all for
taking care of Ye all this time.
Thank you.
Let's go, Ye.
Go on.
Go.
Not going to wait for Xing Wu?
No.
Your phone is ringing.
[Hu]
- Hello?
- Wu.
Qing Ye has left.
Why didn't you come?
When we get back tonight,
we're having dinner with Mr. Meng
and his family.
The house isn't ready yet,
so we'll stay at a hotel tonight.
The hotel is already booked.
Pretty close to home.
I still need to go to the office
and handle some handover stuff.
So for the next couple of days,
just rest at the hotel.
It's not easy to start over.
After this, you'll need to come with me
to visit a few uncles and their families.
To maintain relationships,
you have to keep in touch.
Don't dwell on what happened before.
It's getting late.
Let's head straight to the restaurant.
Your Auntie Meng and the others
are already there.
They want to welcome us back.
Do I have to go?
I'd rather go to the hotel and rest.
Dinner first, then rest.
These six months,
I was in Zhazhating
with no one but Auntie's family.
I went to Meng Rui Hang's house.
Back then, I was naive enough
to think that they would help me.
And now
we are all supposed to sit together
happily again
like nothing ever happened?
Funny
how times change.
I know
you're upset about
how the Mengs treated you before.
But that's in the past.
Give them a way to save face.
Our families still have to stay in touch.
You've already made up your mind.
Why even ask me?
Isn't it about time they got here?
Here they come!
Mr. Qing.
- Ye!
- Hello, Auntie.
Come here, let me take a look at you.
- Hello, Uncle.
- Good.
You look good.
I'm finally at ease.
Take a seat. Mr. Qing, have a seat.
Qing, sit.
- Good to have you back.
- Sit.
Come on.
Let's all
welcome Mr. Qing and Ye back.
- Cheers. Raise your glasses.
- Serve the food.
- Okay.
- Right, right.
- Bring it out.
I got a little emotional
just seeing you two.
Qing,
life has its ups and downs.
Luckily, it was just a false alarm.
It hasn't been easy.
This toast is for you.
May your career reach new heights.
Bottoms up.
Let us join in.
During this time,
Ye and I
owe a lot to all of you for your care.
Going forward,
I'll still need
your continued support.
Let's keep working together sincerely.
Here's to everyone.
You're welcome, Mr. Qing.
Come.
Mr. Qing.
Ye,
aren't you going to toast
your uncles and auntie?
All right.
To
uncles and auntie.
Alright.
Ye,
sit down.
You look thinner than before,
don't you?
You must have suffered quite a bit
out in the countryside all alone, haven't you?
I was so worried
and really felt for you.
But luckily, you're back now.
Always look forward.
Look forward.
Thank you, Auntie Meng.
Actually,
I had a really good time in Zhazhating.
It was
a very rich experience.
And I made some
really good friends.
In Zhazhating,
Wu has got my back,
and I've got yours.
Aim for Qingbei!
Qing Ye, I believe in you.
Win!
Life has all kinds of flavors.
Face it with a smile.
Draw, meld, pong, win!
Be the big winner!
Every day you live is a day you win.
Living is victory.
Qing Ye,
you're a born explorer.
It's time to set sail
and conquer your vast ocean.
This experience
truly taught me
who is worth cherishing
and what is worth remembering.
Well said.
Mr. Qing, Mr. Meng, we're off now.
- Alright.
The wine was quite good today.
Button up. It's a bit cold.
Thanks for the treat, Meng.
Come visit us at home whenever you're free.
I'll cook your favorite dishes.
Next time, it's my treat.
Deal.
Let's get together often.
We're off. Meng.
Mr. Qing, we'll be going now.
- Okay, see you.
- Bye-bye.
Goodbye, Uncle and Auntie.
Remember to come visit us!
Dad,
you go ahead.
I'll look around a bit longer.
Okay.
I'll have Sun pick you up later.